Curriculum Vitae Abhishek Dhiman

Personal details

Contact No.: 9662667244

Location: Accenture BDC8, Bengaluru

Date of Birth: 18th July 1996

Email: sigmasix09@gmail.com

Github Profile: https://github.com/sigmasix09

Portfolio Website: https://sigmasix09.pythonanywhere.com/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/asabhishek09/

Credly Profile: https://www.credly.com/users/abhishek-dhiman.aed00826/



Summary

Software Engineer with expertise in Data Science, Python, Selenium and Automation-Manual testing. Obedient learner with good Analytical, Communicative, Logical & Statistical skills. Looking forward to implement the skills in Data Science, Python, Design-Simulation, CFD, Agile Product Development experience and certifications mastery can be fully utilized.

Professional Experience

Accenture Bengaluru, India

Software Engineer: Python Developer(Google Cloud Platform)

July 2021 to Present

- Development and Enhancement of Accenture Data Catalog API services with Flask and Python.
- Committing code changes to the Git repository and deploying the code for testing.
- Integration of Data Catalog APIs with HTTP security headers and mitigating vulnerabilities.
- Worked on API Access management of users with various roles using JWT token.
- Helping team with preparation of user stories and conducting KT sessions for the new resources.
- Assisting in Dead Lettering Queue (DLQ) deployments i.e Accenture extension for GCP Pub/Sub.

Software Engineer: Test Engineering Analyst

August 2018 to June 2021

- Led automation task using Selenium-Python for Accenture INTIENT Platform and Achieved more than 50% automation for the corresponding release.
- Condensation of automation code templates written in Selenium-Python for the team, increasing the team efficiency by 40% and reducing the deliverable time by 30%.
- Completed python code to automatically check training completion status of employees, reducing manual efforts by approximately 60% 75%.
- Performed in many releases of Rave Adapter, Data Ingestion, Import Export Utility, TechStack Upgrade etc and given many hot-fix with Rework efforts less than 3% for all the releases.
- Designed code snippets for specific complex automation flows and functionalities of applicationspecific modules, increasing release completion time by 30%.
- Creation of Automation code scripts & components using selenium python for the complete applications and specific modules for number of projects.
- Accelerated deliverable time (50% 60%) by preparing reusable modular automation scripts.
- Well communicative and displayed leadership qualities within the team, allowing assignment completion in time and with the best quality.
- Achievements: 1-Team Award. 2-Shining Star Award received for team & individual performance.

Professional Skills

Technical Skills: Data Science, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Cloud Databases, Python, Pandas, Numpy, Analytical & Statistical skills, Python-Flask, Rest APIs, Selenium, SQL, Automation and Manual Testing, Computer Aided Design and Simulation, Computational Fluid Dynamics.

Tools: IBM-Watson Studio, IBM cloud, PyCharm, Jupyter Lab, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, GitLab, JIRA, RTC, RQM, Microsoft Office, Catia V5, Ansys Workbench, Ansys Fluent, ICEM CFD, MATLAB programming, SolidWorks

Certifications

Digitalization in Aeronautics and Space: Professional Certificate (Verified)

Bengaluru, India

Authorized by Technical University of Munich, COURSERA

July 2021 to September 2021

IBM Data Science: Professional Certificate (Verified)

Bengaluru, India

Offered by IBM, COURSERA. Duration (11 months)

April 2021 to July 2021

Project: https://github.com/sigmasix09/Coursera_Capstone

ENGR2000X: A Hands-on Introduction to Engineering Simulations (Verified)

Bengaluru, India

Developed by Cornell University, EDX

November 2020 to February 2021

Python: Beyond the Basics, PluralSight.

Bengaluru, India

Python Programming, Best Pratices. Duration (7.5 hours)

October 2020 to January 2021

Mastering Ansys CFD (Level 1), Udemy.

Bengaluru, India

Ansys Fluent, ICEM CFD, CFX, Tech Plot. Duration (20 hours)

August 2020 to October 2020

Probability and Statistics in Data Science using Python(Verified)

Bengaluru, India

Prepared by UCSanDiegoX, EDX. Duration (120 hours)

May 2020 to August 2020

Python Developer: Zero to Mastery, Udemy.

Bengaluru, India

Conducted by Andrei Neagoie. Duration (30.5 hours)

January 2020 to May 2020

Introduction to Programming with MATLAB, Coursera.

Bengaluru, India

Offered by Vanderbilt University, Nashville. Duration (35 hours)

November 2019 to February 2020

Professional in Product Design and Analysis, CADD Centre. (ID: M160892607)

Bengaluru, India

Catia V5, Solidworks, Ansys Workbench, GD & T workshop.

September 2016 to August 2017

Education

Bachelor of Aeronautical Engineering

Bengaluru, India

<u>Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering</u> [**Grade:** 74.30 % **CGPA:** 7.82 / 10.0] August 2014 to July 2018 **Thesis:** "Analysis of Shockwave Boundary Layer interaction & Assessment of Passive Flow Control Device".

Extracurricular Activities / Hobbies

Inter Collegiate Inter Zone Tournaments [Bengaluru], 42nd (Oct 2012) & 44th (Oct 2014) [Chandigarh] Hobbies: Badminton and Cycling, Story Telling, Cooking and Drawing, Watching Documentries and Anime.